卡门飓风昨天过境
Hurricane Carmen came through here yesterday,
沿途几乎摧毁了一切
destroying nearly everything in its path.
沿海的其他城镇也一样
And as in other towns up and down the coast,
拉巴特湾的捕虾业
Bayou La Batre's entire shrimping industry
成为卡门飓风的最大受害者
has fallen victim to Carmen
渔港完全成了废墟
and has been left in utter ruin.
记者被告知
This reporter has learned,
实际上只有一条捕虾船
in fact, only one shrimping boat
幸免于难
actually survived the storm.
露西 露西 福雷斯来了
Louise. Louise, there's Forrest.
从此以后 捕虾就很容易了
After that, shrimping was easy.
“将会有丰厚的回报”
# There will be great bounty #
“我的上帝…”
# Oh, my God... #
因为人们仍然需要虾
Since people still needed them shrimps
来做虾串烧和虾烧烤什么的
for shrimp cocktails and barbecues and all
而我们的船是唯一剩下的了
and we were the only boat left standing,
他们只能来布巴甘这里买虾
Bubba Gump shrimp's what they got.
我们购置了一大堆船
We got a whole bunch of boats.
有12条珍妮号 还有一个大仓库
12 Jennys, big old warehouse.
我们还订做了帽子
We even have hats
上面写着“布巴甘”
that say "Bubba Gump" on them.
布巴甘捕虾公司
Bubba Gump Shrimp.
这名字家喻户晓
It's a household name.
等等 小兄弟
Hold on there, boy.
你是说你就是…
Are you telling me you're the owner
布巴捕虾公司的老板？
of the Bubba Gump Shrimp Corporation?
对 我们挣了一大堆钱
Yes. We got more money than Davy Crockett.
孩子 我听过很多牛皮
Boy, I heard some whoppers in my time,
这是最大的一个
but that tops them all.
我们身边正坐着一个百万富翁
We were sitting next to a millionaire .